Gobinath Subramani B.Tech., MBA., PGP (Data science)

Data scientist at QuEST Global Engineering Services Private Limited

7,1ST street, Garavepalya, Bangalore, 560068.

gobinathapple@icloud.com | | Mobile: +91 9787347659

Career Summary

Analytics with strong math background and 5+ years of experience using predictive modelling, data processing, and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Involved in Python open source community and passionate about deep reinforcement learning and automation process.

Educational Background:

- PGP in Data Science & analytics from Jaro education and Research Limited in year 2019 with Grade 2.3 out of 3.
- MBA in Human resource management from SSM Academy in year 2017 with 80%.
- Engineering Graduate from SSM College of Engineering in year 2015 with 75 %.
- Higher secondary passed from Government Boys Higher Secondary School in year 2011 with 83%.
- High School passed from Government High School in year 2009 with 86 %.

Experience

- Working as Junior Data scientist in Quest Global Engineering Services Private Limited from Jan 2019 to till now.
- Worked as Analyst in Quest Global Engineering Services Private Limited from May 2016 to Dec 2018.
- Worked as HR Generalist in Magna InfoTech (A Subsidiary of Quess Corp Limited) From Oct 2015 to Apr 2016.
- Worked as **Trainee** in Team source from Jan 2015 to Oct 2015.

Data scientist

Quest Global Engineering Services Private Limited — Bangalore, KA

Job profile

- Responsible for gathering requirements, system analysis, development, testing and deployment.
- Responsible for the python automation as per the customer requirements.
- Professional in designing, developing and enhancing automated test scripts for Selenium using Python.
- Developed test automation framework scripts using Python Selenium WebDriver.

Projects:

1. Project title: Hiring (Recruitment) analytics.

Tools: Excel, company hired employee's data set

Summary: The objective of this project is to find where we can hire more talented employees and which job board. There is a growing shift from traditional intuition-based hiring to the data-driven hiring process in modern-day organizations. This is where analytics comes into the picture, which uses a mix of data and intuition to make hiring decisions. This study highlights the fallacies in traditional methods of hiring and emphasizes the need to use analytics in the recruitment process in companies. The study showcases bottlenecks in the hiring pipeline of the company using recruitment funnel and uses various metrics to check the efficiency of the campus hiring and lateral hiring processes. It also suggests appropriate sources of hiring based on the performance of candidates hired from those sources. Success

profiles of employees in the company have been studied by performing correlations between selection parameters and performance scores. Further, the recruitment strategy and future roadmap of the company are also provided.

2. **Project title:** Attrition prediction analysis using R, Machine learning algorithm.

Tools: R programming, Machine Learning algorithm (Decision Trees (rpart), Random Forests (rf), Support Vactor Models (SVM), Linear Models (glm)).

Summary: This Dissertation aims to help the HR and Project Managers in improving the retention rate of the valuable employees in an organization, thereby minimizing the employee turnover cost of the company. The research was carried out in three stages. To improve the retention rate, efforts were made to first, predict the employee attrition; secondly, decide on which employees are valuable and their retention is profitable to the company. Finally, the factors that influence the employee's intention to resign from a company is found out and provided to the HR and Project managers through the HR Analytical application developed using R. Good amount of research has been done while considering the factors for the employee attrition prediction. Various analysis has been done while selecting the Machine Learning algorithm Decision Trees (rpart),Random Forests (rf),Support Vactor Models (SVM),Linear Models (glm)).We use evaluation of employee performance, monthly salary, performance grade at work and number of years spent in the company, among others, as our features.. The dataset was split, using 80% for training the algorithm and 20% for testing it, achieving an accuracy of 69.32%. Then the separate employee source file was prepared consisting of the valuable employees and who were also a potential candidate for resignation. Then the report was created which shows all the factors influencing employee attrition so that HR and Project managers can use them accordingly retaining valuable employee. This application can be used by the HR Managers to simplify the employee retention decision.

3. **Project title:** Selenium Browser automation for using python

Tools: Python, selenium & google chrome

Summary: In oil & gas industry projects, downloading the customer data from the shared folder is an activity that can spend time, effort, or cost up to 35%. To reduce this, engineers can choose to automate browsers to download the data. Automated browser, especially for downloading the customer data, on web applications can be done by using tools, one of which is Selenium. By default, Selenium is done sequentially and without exploiting multithreading, which has an impact on a sufficiently long time. In this project, a platform that allows Selenium users to download the customer data in google chrome was developed. The result shows that google chrome has proven to be capable of downloading the customer data. Variations occur depending on the functionality being used and also the type of browsers used.

4. Project title: Object detection (corrosion & damage in the machine parts) using Deep learning

Tools: Jyputer Python, tensorflow, openCV, image augmentation

Summary: Computer Vision is the branch of the science of computers and software systems that can recognize as well as understand images and scenes. Computer Vision is consists of various aspects such as image recognition, object detection, image generation, image super-resolution, and many more. Object detection is widely used for face detection, vehicle detection, pedestrian counting, web images, security systems, and self-driving cars. This project aims to find the corrosion & damage parts in the machine through the image, so we are using highly accurate object detection-algorithms and methods such as R-CNN, Fast-RCNN, Faster-RCNN fast yet highly accurate. Using these methods and algorithms,

based on deep learning which is also based on machine learning requires lots of mathematical and deep learning frameworks understanding by using dependencies such as TensorFlow, OpenCV, and image. We can detect each and corrosion & damage parts in the machine in the image by the area object in highlighted rectangular boxes and identify each and every object and assign its tag to the object. This is done by following the steps of pre-processing, Training, Loading the training the model & predications.

HR Generalist

Magna InfoTech — Bangalore, KA

Job profile

- Conducted background checks on candidates by obtaining information from law enforcement officials, previous employers and references.
- Coordinated employment offers with management and extended offers to selected candidates.

Skill Set

Analytical Skills	Data Scientist Skills
Constructing Predictive Models	Python
Critical Thinking	R programming
Data Analysis	Deep learning
Research	Artificial Intelligence (AI)
Testing Hypotheses	Machine learning

Achievements:

- "ON THE FLY 2018" award in Quest Global.
- NSS & JRC volunteer and also leader of school NSS group.

Personal Information:

• Marital Status : Single

Languages Known : English, Tamil, Kannada

Declaration:

The information furnished above is correct to the best of my knowledge.